Lemuel Barango

Full-stack Developer in transit! #ForeverLearningNewThings

Website: lemuelbarango.com

Email: lemuelbarango@gmail.com

I strive to develop quality user interfaces and user experience with design and code. Over the past four years, I have written several web and mobile applications using a range of tech stacks and worked with clients to successfully create a web presence tailored to their specific needs.

My favorite programming languages and frameworks include Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, Sass, Git, Android, and iOS. A year ago, I started exploring a few others like React Native, Node.js, Angular and PHP

When I'm not writing code, I indulge in reading, writing down my thoughts and playing video games. I also do a lot of research and study to keep up with current trends and industry standards in software development.

EXPERIENCE

Iversoft Solutions Inc.

March 2016

Web & Mobile Developer

Developed Web applications and Rest APIs for multiple platforms using, Ruby on rails, Wordpress, Symfony Framework.

Also developed native mobile applications on Android, iOS and cross platform on React Native.

Major Accomplishments

- In less than 3 months I worked with my team to successfully create a multiplatform full-stack sharing economy web application with a rest API in Ruby to meet the client's hard deadlines.
- Implemented TDD across multiple projects in the company and contributed to open source projects like resque-web, spree, parse-server, devise-token-auth, shopify_app, etc.

Go Give-Back

February 2015 - February 2017

Co-Founder & Lead Developer

Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of a startup company – Go Give-Back. Worked with a team of developers to successfully launch a beta android app and then took on the role to develop a release version of the application on Android and iOS, implementing latest design guidelines.

Major Accomplishments

- Created a landing page for the company and added MailChimp and Typeform features to boost conversion rates.
- Worked with a team of software developers to create and maintain the companies native mobile apps on Android/iOS
- Using JavaScript my team developed the backend for the mobile apps and integrated third party APIs like Stripe, Gravatar, Facebook, Twitter, GooglePlus

lemuelbarango.com

January 2014 to December 2016

Web and Mobile Developer

Designing, developing and managing websites and mobile applications for clients. Clients range from individuals to small business and community organizations and associations. I also did a personal project where I created a mobile app on the android platform.

Major Accomplishments

- Created a simple and secure Rails web application for an Apparel company to sell T-shirts and accessories with no upfront capital. checkout https://shoded.com
- Created a mobile-friendly website design for a community of young adults in Gloucester, ON using photoshop and illustrator. Successfully went on to create a fully customizable and SEO friendly WordPress template using HTML5, CSS, SASS, Jquery and PHP

LiveLove.ca February 2016

Volunteer Web Developer

Work with a team of Web designers and developers to update and maintain the public website of http://livelove.ca, using the PHP Larayel framework.

Major Accomplishments

Created internal web application using Ruby on Rails to help administration staff in planning and forecasting.

EDUCATION

University of Ottawa / Université d'Ottawa

September 2011 to December 2015

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) Mathematics and Minor in Physics

My education at the University of Ottawa has helped prepare me in a few ways. Courses like introduction to programming got me interested in computer programming and it's potential. Other courses like analysis, linear algebra and modeling also exposed me to a few real life situations where coding could be applied.

During the course of my program, I also learned to solve problems in a logical / strategic framework.

PROJECTS

Shoded Apparel

February 2016

http://shoded.com

Created a mobile-friendly E-commerce application for a Tshirt Apparel company (http://shoded.com) in Toronto, ON using rails for the backend and integrating stripe for checkout payment.

Go Give-Back
March 2015

Go Give-Back is a donation app that was created during the Startup Weekend (uOttawa). During this weekend I was part of a team that oversaw the development of the app (Android and iOS) - Go Give-Back and we then went on to win the Telfer Business Traction Challenge.